USED BOOK TRADE
(二手書交易)
It's so hot.
熱死了
Let's call it a day for now, otherwise, we'll end up sweating more.
今天就先告一段落吧 不然會流更多汗
Mr. Sajo.
佐城先生
Really a middle school student…?
這是國中生...？
Hello, it's a hot day today.
你好啊 今天也好熱喔
Yes.
是啊
My hair is all sticking together.
我的頭髮都黏在一起了
You should be careful not to have a heat stroke.
要小心別中暑喔
It might be too late already.
可能為時已晚了
Sajo.
佐城同學
(In Five Seconds, Your Foot is About to Launch)
(再五秒妳的腳就要踹到我了)
She's a middle school student with the look of a college girl.
這是宛如女大學生的國中生...
She's a high school girl with the look of a middle school girl.
這是宛如女國中生的高中生...
I'm starting to get confused.
我開始分不清楚了
When it comes to the Phantom Flowlight series,
說到怪盜螢石系列
Imprisoned Princess of the Clock Tower has to be my favorite.
就是要看《囚禁在鐘樓的公主》
I miss that.
真懷念...
Others, like 'The Mobile Armor of the Underground Palace,' were released simultaneously.
同一時期也還有像是 《地下宮殿的移動盔甲》的書
The last chapter is especially well written.
最後一章描寫得非常用心
I've brought this book with me.
我也帶了這本書
Welcome to the Honey Hotel,
妳正在找的
the one you're looking for.
《歡迎蒞臨蜂蜜飯店》
T-This is… out of print.
這是...已經絕版的書
Can I really have it?
真的可以給我嗎
Of course. Do share your thoughts after reading it.
當然可以 看完之後請妳跟我分享心得喔
So this is what it's like when book lovers gather.
原來閱讀愛好者聚在一起是這種感覺
I can't believe Ichinose gives off the impression that she's older.
想不到一之瀨同學看起來還滿成熟的
KEEP IT UP. ARE YOU WORKING? AMAZING. IT'S ALL UP TO YOU NOW
(加油 真努力做事) (好厲害 全靠你了)
I HAVE TO PREPARE FOR THE JUNIORS NEXT. I'M LEAVING IT TO YOU It's the campus open day briefing.
(為了學弟妹準備 交給你了) 是校園參觀日的說明會啊
That guy is terrible at taking pictures.
這傢伙拍照技術真爛
I'm going to save it.
我來存個檔吧
KEEP IT UP
(加油)
ARE YOU WORKING?
(真努力做事)
AMAZING
(好厲害)
IT'S ALL UP TO YOU NOW
(全靠你了)
I HAVE TO PREPARE FOR THE JUNIORS NEXT
(為了學弟妹準備)
DO YOU HAVE TIME TODAY?
(你今天有空嗎)
As usual.
老樣子
Who can understand that?
誰聽得懂啊
-What do you want? -Coffee, cold one.
-妳要什麼 -那個  冰的
Give me.
拿給我
All right, all right.
好好好
You're really something to hang in there.
真虧你能撐得下去耶
I mean your part-time job.
打工
I heard you've been helping with Ichinose's sister.
聽說你還幫忙照顧一之瀨的妹妹
What? Where…
什麼？居然...
AGAINST VIOLENCE Where… did you hear that?
妳從哪聽來的...
Never underestimate my information network as student council vice president.
你可別小看我這個 學生會副會長的情報網
What does this have to do with the student council?
這跟學生會有什麼關係...
So you heard it from senior Shinomiya, didn't you?
妳是聽四之宮學姊說的嗎
You're the one who works hard, sis.
老姊妳才是吧
Even though you're the vice president, I can't believe you can work so late.
就算妳是副會長 也真虧妳能忙到那麼晚
You keep complaining about how annoying it is.
明明嘴上抱怨著有夠麻煩
You're such a working slave.
妳這不是很有社畜精神嗎
What?
怎樣
Can't I work hard?
我就不能認真做事嗎
Your foot! In five seconds, your foot is about to launch.
妳的腳...再五秒就要踹到我了
In that regard,
話說回來
if you have time to work part-time,
你有閒打工的話
could you assist in the preparations for the campus open day?
不如來幫忙我們準備校園參觀日
Doesn't each class already send two people to help?
每個班級不是都派出兩個人幫忙了嗎
They are in charge of directing the junior high students.
班級派來的人負責幫國中生帶路
This year, however, there are too many visitors,
但今年來參觀的人太多了
so Rin is running out of hands.
所以凜那邊人手不夠
Even if the student council wants to assist,
就算學生會想去幫忙
we are already overburdened due to the large workload.
但現在因為工作量過大 導致我們忙不過來了
Sounds pretty terrible.
聽起來很糟糕呢
Even so, why should I help?
話雖如此 為什麼我要去幫忙...
You'll have time after work in the evening, right?
晚上打完工後你就有時間了吧
I don't want to owe Rin a favor.
我不想欠凜人情
Please.
拜託你了
Owing a favor? Is it that exaggerated?
還欠人情...有那麼誇張嗎
After you rejected Rin, she's been complaining to me.
自從你拒絕了凜 她就不停跟我抱怨
You better think of a solution.
你快想想辦法
I don't think
我認為我實在
I'm cut out for a position on the student council.
無法勝任風紀委員一職
Allow me to say no.
請容我拒絕
No. I only declined the invitation to join the student council.
我也不過就是拒絕了 加入風紀委員會的邀約而已
What I mean is that you should explain to Rin clearly.
我的意思是叫你跟凜解釋清楚
Really?
真的要嗎...
I'm struggling to manage my friend's relationship with my brother.
我朋友因為我弟的關係而煩惱 我夾在中間也很為難啊
Did I unknowingly owe my older sister many favors?
難不成我在不知不覺間 欠了老姊很多人情嗎
You must hate it when someone brings up this topic when you're busy, right?
她忙得要死的時候還要面對這種事 想必很麻煩吧
Alright, I'll help, okay?
好啦 我去幫忙就是了
I'll be there to make my mark.
我會去大展身手
If you help, she should be really happy, right?
你去幫忙的話 她應該會很高興吧
Obviously, she doesn't want to be disliked by you.
她很顯然不想被你討厭
Don't say that, it makes it hard for me.
妳別這樣說 我會很難做事
I think to Rin,
對凜來說
you're probably more than just my younger brother.
你應該不只是我弟弟這麼簡單吧
Drink it.
拿去
Here's your phone.
手機給你
Hello?
喂？
Is this Senior Shinomiya?
請問是四之宮學姊嗎
Huh? Who are you? Where's Kaede?
你是誰 楓呢
She is sleeping next to me.
我老姊在我旁邊睡覺
Don't act like you're my boyfriend.
你以為你是我男朋友啊
My ear, my ear! Stop pulling, it's about to be pulled off!
我的耳朵...要被妳扯掉了啦
Sajo? Why are you calling me?
佐城？你找我幹嘛
Long time no see, Senior Shinomiya.
四之宮學姊 好久不見了
I have something to talk to you.
我有事想找妳聊聊
So I borrowed my sister's phone. Ouch!
所以借了我老姊的手機...好痛啊
I see.
這樣啊
Kaede, let him go.
楓 妳就放開他吧
Sajo said he had something to talk to me, right?
佐城說他有事找我
My ear on this side has definitely gotten bigger.
我這隻耳朵絕對被拉大了
It's become a lucky ear.
變成招風耳了啦
The campus open day is coming up soon, right?
校園參觀日就快到了對吧
I was wondering if there's anything I can help with.
我想說不知道自己能不能幫上忙
What? Is that all?
你想找我聊的就是這個啊
You don't need to worry about it.
你不必在意
I'll figure out a solution here.
我自己會想辦法解決
What?
什麼...
Was I just politely rejected?
我被婉拒了
Senior, you don't have to be so polite.
學姊妳不用這麼客氣
Out of my personal interest, I also want to see you.
我自己本身也想見見學姊妳啊
What? Personal interest?
啊？你自己想...
What are you saying?
你突然說什麼奇怪的話啊
It's nothing, just consider it a young boy's joke.
沒啦 妳就當作是少年的玩笑話吧
But if there's anything I can help with, just say it.
但如果真的需要幫手 妳就儘管說吧
Um…
呃 這個嘛...
To be honest, I'm very grateful for your willingness to help.
老實說我很感謝你願意幫忙
But it's a lot of manual labor, is that okay?
但都是些勞力工作 你可以嗎
As long as it's for you, it's a piece of cake.
只要是為了四之宮學姊 輕而易舉啦
What?
什麼啊
DURING THE SUMMER VACATION, THIS DOOR IS NOT OPEN PLEASE GO TO THE FRONT DESK FOR ANY BUSINESS, STUDENT COUNCIL
(此扇門暑假不開放) (有事請繞至接待處 學生會)
Well… Long time no see.
那個...好久不見
It's been less than a month since we last met.
呃 離我們上次見面還不到一個月呢
T-That's true.
這倒也是...
What is it that makes you so uncomfortable?
學姊妳在尷尬個什麼勁啊
Please continue to treat your junior with grace and affection as before.
請像之前一樣落落大方地疼愛學弟
Can I take this to mean
我可以理解為...
that you want to join the student council?
你願意加入風紀委員會了嗎
That's a different thing.
這是兩碼子事
Did this matter give you such a big blow?
這件事讓妳打擊這麼大嗎
When you broke free from Yuyu's grip in the canteen,
那次你在食堂甩掉由結的手
you held her hand again
然後又握住她的手
before fleeing in terror.
最後再落荒而逃
I'm wondering if my disregard
我在想 會不會因為我忽略你的感受
for your feelings has irritated Yuyu.
反而惹由結生氣了...
Senior Inatomi?
稻富學姊嗎
Right, you've always been concerned about her feelings.
也是啦 妳一直很在意她的感受
Because this person likes Senior Inatomi the most.
這個人真的是很喜歡稻富學姊呢
So you're just a little uncomfortable with me,
這麼說 妳對我只是感到有點尷尬
which means you're not too concerned about our relationship, right?
就表示妳也沒多煩惱跟我的關係吧
That's not true.
才沒這回事
I even wish you could become my little brother.
我甚至希望你能變成我弟弟
Why?
不是 為什麼啊
It's manual labor anyway, isn't it?
反正都是些粗活對吧
I can't bear the thought of making our beloved Senior Inatomi sweat.
我可不能讓可愛的稻富學姊流汗啊
Are you really willing to do it?
你真的願意嗎
Why do your words seem prickly to me?
我怎麼覺得你話中帶刺
It's just your imagination.
妳太多心了啦
I-Is that so…?
是嗎...
Maybe because she's too straightforward.
或許是因為她個性太直了
She can't quite catch the joke.
她有點聽不出玩笑話啊
Anyway, it's strange to chat here.
總之 站在這裡聊也怪怪的
Let's go.
我們走吧
The class representatives are primarily in charge
學生會跟班級代表負責的工作
of guiding middle school students on school tours.
主要是帶領國中生參觀學校
In contrast,
相較之下
the student council is in charge of moving equipment and setting up the venue.
風紀委員會則負責 搬運器材和佈置會場
They are the silent contributors.
也就是在背後默默付出的角色
That's right.
沒錯
But the problem
但問題在於
is that most of them are girls.
風紀委員會裡絕大多數都是女生
Although it can be solved if there are enough people, it is extremely dangerous
雖然人數也不是不夠
for only girls to move things. I hope to reduce this risk.
但只靠女生搬東西還是很危險 我希望盡量減少風險
How much assistance can I provide?
就憑我一個人幫忙夠嗎
Without saying anything else,
我想不必我多說你也明白
I believe you understand that there are some things that only you can do.
有些事情只能交給你了
Regardless of how simple the work appears,
無論看似多簡單的工作
the organizer has responsibilities and confidentiality obligations.
都伴隨著主辦責任和保密義務
I believe that if it's you, there will be no problem.
我相信你一定沒問題的
There is no better opportunity
想在女生面前展現我的男子氣概
for girls to see my manly side than this.
這是絕佳的機會了
You jerk.
你這傢伙
Hey… so heavy!
呃...好重啊
So rude.
你真沒禮貌
Please keep in mind that you are
各位帶領學生參觀時
the Koetsu High School representative when giving students a tour.
請記住自己是鴻越高中的代表
Representative…
代表...
CAMPUS OPEN DAY, PRE-BRIEFING Although it's an unwritten rule,
雖然是不成文的規定
PLEASE SIT DOWN AFTER YOU GET THE MATERIALS class representatives are usually good looking,
(校園參觀日 事前說明會) (拿到資料後請就座) 班級代表一般都是長相端正
outstanding students.
(校園參觀日 事前說明會) (拿到資料後請就座) 成績優秀的學生
But our homeroom teacher picked those who weren't in any clubs first.
但我們班導優先選擇沒參加社團的人
There are such classes, huh.
也有些班級會這樣吧
I see.
原來如此
Having to rely on these exceptional students
靠這些活躍又充實的學生
makes middle school students yearn for our school.
讓國中生對我們學校抱有憧憬
Very reasonable.
這很合理
Yeah… Then naturally, Natsukawa will be here.
對喔...夏川當然也在這裡
With Sasaki?
她跟佐佐木一起啊
Although they match well,
雖然他們很相配...
it's just too coincidental.
真是太不湊巧了
Hey, what's wrong with you?
喂 你怎麼了
No, nothing.
沒什麼
What's wrong? Sasaki.
佐佐木同學 你怎麼了
Just now…
剛才...
No, it's nothing.
沒什麼啦
STUDENT COUNSELING CENTER
(學生指導室)
Long time no see, Sajo.
好久不見 佐城同學
So our helper is Sajo.
原來佐城同學是我們的幫手啊
Thank you for helping us.
請多指教
Hello everyone, I'm glad to join you.
請大家多多指教
Recently,
最近啊
Mina has been talking about Sajo all the time.
深那她開口閉口都是佐城同學的事
Exactly.
對啊
I-Is that so?
啊...是嗎
That introverted Mina is surprisingly able to laugh so happily.
內向的深那居然會笑得那麼開心
Her part-time job must be very fulfilling, right?
想必她的打工生活一定很充實
I think so.
應該是吧...
Thank you, Sajo.
謝謝你 佐城同學
He's a nice guy, though as an older brother,
雖然他是個太溺愛妹妹的哥哥
he's a little too spoiled for his sister.
但基本上應該算是個好人吧
Ichinose is not here today.
今天一之瀨同學也不在
He wouldn't lose control like before, would he?
他應該不會像之前那樣失控吧
So,
那請問...
what should I do?
我應該做些什麼呢
Oh yes, this…
對了 這個嘛
Firstly…
首先是...
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《滿懷美夢的少年是現實主義者》
There are no more questions, right?
大家都沒有問題了嗎
Today is the last day of the briefing.
那今天就是最後一次舉辦說明會了
We are counting on everyone on the day of the campus open day
校園參觀日當天就麻煩大家了
Natsukawa.
夏川
What is it?
怎麼了
This week…
這禮拜...
The soccer club is having an internal practice match.
足球隊要舉辦練習賽
Would you like to see it if possible?
妳要不要來看呢
I have to look after my sister, so I'm afraid I won't be able to go.
我得照顧我妹 可能沒辦法...
Oh, right.
是嗎
I'm sorry.
對不起
Given that you've already invited me.
你特地邀請我了 我卻...
No, it's nothing.
沒什麼啦
But, thank you.
不過還是謝謝你
You're welcome.
不客氣
How's Airi lately? I really want to see her again.
小愛梨最近好嗎 我好想再看看她
Well…
這個嘛...
She's doing well.
嗯
Natsukawa, are you not going to karaoke?
夏川同學 妳不去唱歌嗎
Everyone said they are going.
大家都要去耶
I'm sorry, I have something at home.
抱歉 我家裡有點事
-Really? -What a pity.
-是嗎 -真可惜
I'm sorry.
抱歉哦
Not at all.
不會啦
We had a feeling it would end up this way.
我們大概也猜到會這樣了
Goodbye.
再見囉
Back then, I didn't have the luxury of time
我那時候完全沒有餘力
or the luxury of thought.
我沒有時間也沒有心情...
The disparity between my classmates
看著每天都過得很開心的同學
and my own situation,
我的境遇卻跟他們不同
as well as the self-control to never feel lost or anxious
面對這種差異的時候
in the face of this disparity,
我克制自己絕不能感到失落或焦慮
but as the complexities of this emotion grew,
但隨著這份複雜的情緒逐漸高漲
I was on the verge of a breakdown.
我面臨了崩潰邊緣
Okay, I'll go right away.
好 我馬上來
Natsukawa?
夏川同學？
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
I'm fine.
我沒事
I cared about him at the time
當時我會上前關心他
not because I was gentle and kind,
並不是因為我善良親切
but because
而是因為
I saw my own reflection
我從茫然無助的他身上
in his lost and helpless figure.
看到了自己的影子
That's all.
僅此而已
Hello.
妳好
Thank you for helping me yesterday.
謝謝妳昨天幫了我
It's nothing.
啊...沒什麼
I'm Sajo Wataru.
我叫佐城涉
Natsukawa Aika,
夏川愛華同學
your gentleness made me fall in love with you at first sight.
妳的溫柔讓我對妳一見鍾情了
Will you consider dating me?
妳可以跟我交往嗎
I'm sorry,
對不起
I'm not in the mood right now.
我現在沒那種心情
I see.
是喔...
May I ask why?
妳可以告訴我理由嗎
Because I am too busy,
我太忙了
so I can't imagine myself
所以我無法想像
dating someone else.
自己跟別人交往的樣子
Too busy? Because of club activities?
妳是因為社團活動太忙了嗎
I'm not going to talk about myself.
我並不打算跟你多聊我的狀況
Natsukawa.
啊 夏川同學
Good morning.
早安
I can still go to school with you, right?
我們至少可以一起去上學吧
Since then,
從那時候開始
he always appeared in front of me.
他就常常出現在我面前
Natsukawa,
夏川同學
can you help me with this question?
妳教一下我這題好嗎
Can I call you by your first name?
我可以直接叫妳的名字嗎
Please let me call you by your first name, please.
請讓我稱呼妳的名字吧 拜託
Aika, I can help you carry things. Let's go together.
愛華 我幫妳拿東西 我們一起走吧
He's always cheerful, cheeky,
他一直很嗨 臉皮也很厚
and upbeat.
又很樂觀
Why should I teach you?
我幹嘛教你啊
I refuse.
我拒絕
No.
我不要
No matter how cruel I was to him,
無論我對他多兇
his feelings for me never seemed to change.
他的心意似乎都不會改變
Aika, you are the best!
愛華妳果然是最棒的
Natsukawa,
夏川同學
I heard that you've been bothered by a weird boy?
聽說妳被奇怪的男生纏上了
Because you're cute, Natsukawa.
畢竟夏川同學妳太可愛了
It's inevitable.
在所難免嘛
- I'll protect you if you're in danger. - I don't know since when,
-要是妳遇到危險我會保護妳 -不知不覺之間
classmates often come to talk to me.
同學們變得經常來找我聊天
Looking back,
現在回想起來
chatting with him and others relieved me,
多虧跟他還有其他人聊天
who was on the verge of collapsing.
讓崩潰邊緣的我感到輕鬆許多
As the Senior High School Entrance Examination approached,
後來接近升學考試時
he temporarily stopped looking for me.
他有段時間都沒有來找我
ELIGIBLE CANDIDATES, EXAM NUMBER
(合格榜單 考生號碼)
Mom, I passed.
媽媽 我考上了
Yes, that's right, great.
對 沒錯 太好了
Thank you, I'm finally relieved.
謝謝 我終於鬆了一口氣
Aika,
愛華
congratulations on passing!
恭喜妳考上了
Could you also congratulate me?
妳可以也跟我說聲恭喜嗎
So you are also going to Koetsu High School too?
原來你也是考鴻越高中啊
I wanted to go to the same high school as you,
因為我想跟妳上同一間高中
so I studied hard.
就努力讀書了
Wait. Don't do that!
等等...你別這樣
This isn't junior high.
這裡又不是國中
Is that not allowed?
不行嗎
Of course not.
當然不行了
Then address me by my given name,
那妳用我的名字稱呼我吧
not you or Sajo.
不要叫我“你”或佐城
You're really weird.
你很莫名其妙耶
Please.
求求妳
I get it. Stop bowing.
我知道了啦 你別再求我了
Yay!
好耶
Natsukawa, you are very popular.
夏川同學妳很受歡迎耶
You mean him, right?
妳是在說他吧
He's just pestering me without permission.
那只是他擅自纏著我罷了
Sajo? He's quite humorous, isn't he?
小佐城他很有趣耶
Sajo?
什麼“小佐城”啊…
His attitude remained unchanged
上了高中之後
after we entered high school.
他的態度也依然沒變
However,
但是
Kei and other people began to appear around me.
我的身邊出現了圭還有各式各樣的人
Despite the fact that it was not the high school life
雖然跟我想像的高中生活
I had imagined,
有點不太一樣
I spent every day relatively fulfilled.
但我還是度過了挺充實的日子
That's what I believe.
我是這麼認為的...
Aika!
愛華愛華
What? Were you waiting for me?
怎麼了 莫非妳在等我嗎
How could--
怎麼可...
Huh? Wait a minute!
咦 等等
What's wrong with you?
妳怎麼了嗎
Nothing.
沒什麼
What are you planning to do later?
妳待會打算幹嘛
Go home.
回家...
I see.
是嗎
Right.
也對啦
Were you thinking of Sajo?
妳...是不是很在意佐城啊
W-Why would you ask that?
你...為什麼這麼問
Well…
該怎麼說...
Um…
那個...
Sorry, my sister is looking for me.
抱歉 我妹打來了
What's wrong?
什麼事嗎
THE PART-TIME JOB SITUATION APPEARS TO BE RESOLVED SMOOTHLY. THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP
(打工的事好像能順利解決了) (謝謝妳的建議)
Wataru?
阿涉
I've caused you a lot of trouble before.
我之前造成妳很多困擾
I came to tell you that I won't bother you anymore.
我想跟妳說 我不會再纏著妳了
Hey, Natsukawa.
喂 夏川
So lonely.
好寂寞...
What am I saying?
我在說什麼啊
Really, this is nonsense.
真是的 莫名其妙
What am I thinking about?
胡思亂想什麼...
Idiot.
笨蛋
Found you!
他在那裡...
Good morning, Aika.
愛華早安
I got it! Just like you said, Aika.
我懂了 愛華妳說的沒錯
You're really amazing, Aika.
愛華妳真厲害
And very cute.
而且又可愛
What?
什麼嘛...
Really…
真的是...
Ouch.
好痛...
Na-Natsukawa?
夏...夏川
Wataru?
阿涉...
Ouch.
好痛喔...
What are you rushing off to so quickly?
妳怎麼這麼匆忙啊？